# Laura Andrea Mujica

# Visual Designer

Córdoba, AR · +54-9-351-2481479 · hola@laumujica.com.ar · linkedin.com/in/lauraamujica · behance.net/lauraamujica

As a curious, self-taught individual, I am recognized for my quick thinking and abundance of ideas. Throughout my +10 years of experience in graphic design, I enhanced my skills and developed methodologies that streamlined project development from start to finish. My focus is always on understanding and meeting human needs and desires. I particularly enjoy working with typography and color matching, and I take great pride in my ability to meticulously search for and eliminate design imperfections to ensure the highest level of quality in the final product.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# **Graphic Design Teacher**

August 2019 - October 2022

Independent, Córdoba, AR

- Trained +30 students on design software such as Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop, InDesign, and Corel Draw.
- Instructed students about design principles and reduced their skill insecurities by at least 75%.
- Developed assignments and projects that engaged students, resulting in a 70% increase in their commitment.
- · Coached small business owner students to design faster and save at least 3 hours per project.
- Mentored students to exceed course objectives, achieving a 100% completion rate for every course.

## **Freelance Visual Designer**

August 2019 - November 2021

Technosur, Córdoba, AR

- · Designed visuals that represented the organization or client's needs, resulting in a 75% increase in their visibility.
- Developed +15 logos, business cards, and websites for clients (using Google Sites + personal domain).
- Wrote 360° proposals and estimates for design projects and negotiated contracts with clients, achieving a 100% acceptance rate for offers.
- Collaborated with other designers, copywriters, and vendors and expanded my network by 80%.

# Jr. Graphic Designer

August 2018 - March 2019

Oferta Gráfica, Córdoba, AR

- · Prepared and organized original files for 3 different types of printing systems: offset, digital, and solvent printing.
- Supported for pre- and post-production of plotter printing and reduced production time by 20 hours per week.
- · Led the creation of graphic design of internal pieces for the company, reducing the responsibilities of seniors by 50%.
- Processed +120 orders through the online platform & Mercado Libre, ensuring timely delivery and customer satisfaction.

# **Freelance Graphic Designer**

February 2011 - February 2018

Ideas Nómade, Córdoba, AR

- Created +100 logos and minimal visual identity for small entrepreneurs and businesses through research, interviews, and in-person meetings.
- Designed, printed, serially produced, and bound annual agendas over a +3 years period.
- Gained +200 clients by innovating handmade binding products and processes in Córdoba city.
- Directed photography at events with professional equipment for 2 years, including photo editing and retouching and creation of photo books.

## **EDUCATION**

# **Associate Degree in Advertising**

Colegio Universitario IES, Córdoba, AR — February 2007 – November 2011

## **COURSES & CERTIFICATIONS**

# **UX/UI Design**

Coderhouse – August 2022 – November 2022

## Web Development

Coderhouse – August 2022 – November 2022

#### Manual QA Testing

Coderhouse - July 2022 - August 2022

#### **Design Thinking**

Scrum México – June 2022 – July 2022

#### **LANGUAJES**

English: C2 Proficient (EF SET Certificate)

# **TOOLS & SKILLS**

Adobe Creative Studio, Figma, HTML & CSS, Optimal Workshop, UX/UI, Usability Research, Wireframing & Prototyping, Mockup, Journey Map, Visual Design, Storyboards, Branding, Web Design, User Interface Design, Design Systems, Innovation, Empathy, Design Thinking